Records of the Elmira Travel Club
Elmira College
Records of the Elmira Travel Club
1905 - 2003
The collection consists of meeting minutes, programs, awards and scrapbooks.
3 linear ft. (3 boxes)
Elmira College Archives,Gannett-Tripp Library, Elmira College, Elmira, N.Y.
Unrestricted.
The Elmira Travel Club was organized in 1904 to promote the history, art and literature of the U.S. and other countries. The club was federated in 1909, becoming a member of the New York State Federation of Women’s Clubs.
In 1951 the club became a member of the General Federation of Women’s Clubs. The Club over the years has contributed to various state and national projects and funded many campaign including campaigns during both World Wars.
The Club instituted a community improvement program and received numerous awards from the General Federation of Women’s Clubs during its 100 year history.
The Elmira Travel Club appears to have been dissolved in 2003.
Elmira Travel Club; New York State Federation of Women’s Clubs; General Federation of Women’s Clubs; Women—Societies and Clubs; Elmira (N.Y.)—History; Women—New York (State)--Elmira; minutes (administrative records); scrapbooks; photobooks; trade books
The bulk of the collection is minute books from the club’s inception in 1904 until 2003. The minute book for years 1910 to 1915 is missing. The collection also contains a year book for all years, 1906-2000. Annual reports, bylaws, miscellaneous documents, awards, pamphlets and scrapbooks complete the collection.
ORGANIZATIONAL NOTE:
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1: Minute Books [1905-2003]
Series 2: Miscellaneous Materials [1906-2000]
Series 3: Other Formats [undated]
- SERIES 1: MINUTE BOOKS [1905-2003], SERIES NOTE: This series is missing one minute book from 1905-1910. The series is organized chronologically.
  - Minute Book 1 [1905-1910] (Box-folder 1 1)
  - Minute Book 3 [1915-1920] (Box-folder 1 2)
  - Minute Book 4 [1920-1927] (Box-folder 1 3)
  - Minute Book 5 [1927-1934] (Box-folder 1 4)
  - Minute Book 6 [1934-1940] (Box-folder 1 5)
  - Minute Book 7 [1940-1947] (Box-folder 1 6)
  - Minute Book 8 [1947-1957] (Box-folder 1 7)
  - Minute Book 9 [1957-1968] (Box-folder 1 8)
  - Minute Book 10 [1968-1973] (Box-folder 1 9)
  - Minute Book 11 [1973-1979] (Box-folder 1 10)
  - Minute Book 12 [1980-1984] (Box-folder 1 11)
  - Minute Book 13 [1984-1992] (Box-folder 1 12)
  - Minute Book 14 [1992-1999] (Box-folder 1 13)
  - Minute Book 15 [2000-2003] (Box-folder 1 14)
- SERIES 2: MISCELLANEOUS MATERIALS [1906-2000], SERIES NOTE: This series is arranged alphabetically by folder title. The files are not thorough representations of the folder titles and contain limited information.
  - Certification of Club and Citations of Achievement -- Presented as a member of the New York State Federation of Women's Clubs and/or the General Federation of Women's Clubs [1952-1999] (Box-folder 2 1)
  - History of the Elmira Travel Club [1982-1987, undated] (Box-folder 2 2)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs -- Local events [1944-1956] (Box-folder 2 3)
  - Program Books (Yearbooks) [1906-1930] (Box-folder 2 4)
  - Program Books (Yearbooks) [1931-1960] (Box-folder 2 5)
  - Program Books (Yearbooks) [1961-2000] (Box-folder 2 6)
  - A Manual for Club Women -- Book [1929] (Box-folder 2 7)
  - Annual Reports -- Primarily reports from the 1990's [1957-1999] (Box-folder 2 8)
  - Photo Album [1990-1991] (Box-folder 2 9)
  - Robert's Rules of Order Revised -- Book [1915] (Box-folder 2 10)
  - Scrap Book [1957-1963] (Box-folder 3 1)
  - Scrap Book [1963-1980] (Box-folder 3 2)
  - Scrap Book [1959-2000] (Box-folder 3 3)
- SERIES 3: OTHER FORMATS [undated], SERIES NOTE: This series contains 3 dimensional objects.
  - 1 - Copper Stamp (1) [undated] (Box-folder 3 4)
  - 2 - Copper Stamp (2) [undated] (Box-folder 3 5)
  - 3 – N.Y.S.F.W.C President's Pin [undated] (Box-folder 3 6)